# Shivam Duggal

**✓** shivamduggal.9507@gmail.com

🗘 ShivamDuggal4 💆 ShivamDuggal4 🗗 Shivam Duggal 🧥 shivamduggal4.github.io

## RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests lie at the intersection of computer vision, graphics, and robotics. I am interested in topics such as self-supervised learning, physics-based vision, 2D/3D scene understanding (perception, reconstruction & simulation), with applications relating to augmented virtual reality and robotics.

# EDUCATION

## Carnegie Mellon University

Aug 2021 - Present

Masters of Science in Robotics (MSR)

Pittsburgh, USA

- CGPA: 4.16/4 (till 2nd semester\*)
- Awards: Siebel Scholar (1/5 CMU students, only masters student)

# Delhi Technological University (DTU, formerly DCE)

Aug 2013 - Aug 2017

Bachelor in Technology, Computer Science (B. Tech)

Delhi, India

- Aggregate: 83.7%, **CGPA: 9.12/10** 

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Carnegie Mellon University

Aug 2021 - Present

Graduate Student Researcher

Pittsburgh, USA

- Advisors: Prof. Deepak Pathak

## **Brown University**

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Research Intern

Remote

- Advisor: Prof. Srinath Sridhar

## **Uber Advanced Technology Group**

Nov 2019 - Feb 2021

Research Scientist I

Toronto, Canada

- Advisors: Prof. Raquel Urtasun, Prof. Shenlong Wang

#### **Uber Advanced Technology Group**

Aug 2018 - Nov 2019

AI Resident (3 AI residents selected world-wide)

Toronto, Canada

- Advisors: Prof. Raquel Urtasun, Prof. Shenlong Wang

#### Awards & Honors

[\* Denotes All India National rank]

	Siebel Scholarship (\$35000 USD)	2023
Top $4.2\%$	Outstanding Reviewer ECCV	2022
$\mathbf{Top}  0.2\%$	GeoSim nominated as Best Paper Candidate CVPR	2021
Rank $1/70$	Marketplace Hackathon, Amazon	2017
Rank $20/7937^*$	Codechef June Long Challenge	2017
Rank $10/1885^*$	Hackerearth Collegiate Programming Contest	2016
Rank <b>28</b> *	ACM ICPC India Finals	2016
Rank <b>29/2609</b> *	ACM ICPC Amritapuri Regionals	2016

Rank $29/867^*$	ACM ICPC Chennai Preliminary Round	2016
Rank $12/5693^*$	Codechef October Long Challenge	2016
Rank $1/130$ Interns	Flipkart Hackathon JUGAAD	2016
Rank <b>6</b> *	IEEEXtreme Programming Competition	2015
Rank 8*	IEEEXtreme Programming Competition	2014

#### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS & PREPRINTS

[\* Denotes equal contribution]

- [1] <u>Shivam Duggal</u>, Deepak Pathak. "Topologically-Aware Deformation Fields for Single-View 3D Reconstruction." (CVPR 2022) [Link]
- [2] Trevor Houchens, Cheng-You Lu, Shivam Duggal, Rao Fu, Srinath Sridhar. "NeuralODF: Learning Omnidirectional Distance Fields for 3D Shape Representation." [Link]
- [3] Shivam Duggal\*, Zihao Wang\*, Wei-Chiu Ma, Sivabalan Manivasagam, Justin Liang, Shenlong Wang, Raquel Urtasun. "Mending Neural Implicit Modeling for 3D Reconstruction in the Wild." (WACV 2022) [Link]
- [4] Yun Chen\*, Frieda Rong\*, Shivam Duggal\*, Shenlong Wang, Xinchen Yan, Sivabalan Manivasagam, Shangjie Xue, Ersin Yumer, Raquel Urtasun. "GeoSim: Realistic Video Simulation via Geometry-Aware Composition for Self-Driving." (CVPR 2021) [Link]
  Nominated for Best Paper Award!
- [5] Shivam Duggal, Shenlong Wang, Wei-Chiu Ma, Rui Hu, Raquel Urtasun. "Deeppruner: Learning efficient stereo matching via differentiable patchmatch." (ICCV 2019) [Link]
- [6] Shamit Lal\*, Shivam Duggal\*, Indu Sreedevi. "Online video summarization: Predicting future to better summarize present." (WACV 2019) [Link]

#### Industry Experience

Amazon, Hyderabad, India	(Software Eng.)	Aug 2017 - Jul 2018
Flipkart, Bangalore, India	(Software Eng. Intern)	Jun 2016 - Aug 2016
Parallel Dots, Delhi, India	(Machine Learning Intern)	Dec 2015 - Jan 2016

# Conference Reviewing

CVPR 2023 / WACV 2023 / 3DV 2022 / ECCV 2022 / CVPR 2022 / WACV 2022 / IJCV WACV 2021 / ICRA 2021 / IROS 2021 / SIGGRAPH Asia 2021

# Course Work

Computational Photography / Physics-Based Rendering (A+) / Computer Vision (A+) Convex Optimization (A) / Math for Robotics (A)

#### SKILLS

Languages/ Tools & Frameworks: Python, C/C++, LATEX, Pytorch, Git, AWS

#### PATENTS

- [1] <u>Shivam Duggal</u>, Shenlong Wang, Wei-Chiu Ma, Raquel Urtasun."Depth Estimation for Autonomous Devices." US Patent App. 16/826,924
- [2] Frieda Rong, Yun Chen, Shivam Duggal, Shenlong Wang, Xinchen Yan, Sivabalan Manivasagam, Ersin Yumer, Raquel Urtasun. "Photorealistic Image Simulation with Geometry-Aware Composition." US Patent App. 17/150,989

# OTHER PROJECTS

#### Non-Exponential Radiative Transfer for Light Transport

CMU, Pittsburgh

- Studied the Radiative Transfer Framework (RTE) which governs the physics of light transport through a participating medium.
- Classical RTE models light transmittance (as an exponential function) only through spatially-uncorrelated participating mediums. We explored the affect of spatially-correlated participating mediums on RTE, by modeling light transmittance as non-exponential functions.

# Poisson Solver for Depth Completion

Uber ATG, Toronto

- Casted the problem of monocular depth completion using single camera image and sparse Lidar points, to a boundary value problem.
- Instead of directly predicting depth value per pixel, we developed an approach to first predict relative-depth estimates per pixel and then integrate them to predict the final depth value.

## Emotion Recognition on speech signals

DTU, India

- Implemented ensemble approaches and compared various algorithms for emotion recognition in speech signals using MFCC and energy as features.
- Publication: Emotion recognition on speech signals using machine learning, ICBDACI (2017) [Link]